Guide to the Bernard Augustine De Voto Papers, 1918-1955 (inclusive), 1944-1951 (bulk) M0001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Bernard Augustine De Voto Papers,
1918-1955 (inclusive), 1944-1951 (bulk)
M0001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
63.0 Linear feet
Correspondence, typescripts and galley proofs of 19 major works, 166 articles, 25 short fiction and non-fiction papers, broadcasts, speeches, lectures, and other papers. The correspondence (1948-55) with Harper's magazine relates to DeVoto's column The Easy Chair, and includes letters from Harper's magazine to senders of letters of condolence, and letters concerning DeVoto. Includes research material used in DeVoto's literary writings and in his work relating to politics, conservation and reclamation, free speech, national parks, and Western Americana. Correspondents include many of the leading persons in contemporary literature, politics, education, and the arts.
De Voto, Bernard Augustine, 1897-1955
Biographical Note
1897 Born, January 11, Ogden, Utah.
1902 Began schooling at Sacred Heart Academy, Ogden.
1910 Entered Ogden High School.
1914 Graduated Ogden H.S.; entered University of Utah.
1915 Entered Harvard College as a sophomore.
1917 Enlisted U.S. Army, to 1919.
1920 Harvard graduation; return to Ogden.
1922 Appointed as Instructor, Northwestern University.
1923 Married Helen Avis MacVicar.
1924 The Crooked Mile.
1925 "Ogden: The Underwriting of Salvation."
1926 The Chariot of Fire.
1927 Writer's Handbook, A Manual of English Composition. Moved to Lincoln, Mass.
1928 The House of Sun-Goes-Down.
1929 Began part-time teaching at Harvard; instructor and tutor, 1929-1934; lecturer, 1934-36.
1930 Americana Deserta Editor of Harvard Graduate's Magazine, 1930-32. Birth of a son, Gordon King.
1932 Mark Twain's America.
1934 We Accept With Pleasure.
1935 Harper's Magazine.
1936 The Saturday Review of Literature; moved to New York City. Forays and Rebuttals.
1937 Awarded honorary Litt. D. by Middlebury College.
1938 The Saturday Review of Literature
1939 Troubled Star.
1940 Birth of a son, Mark Mark Twain in Eruption Minority Report. Rain Before Seven.
1942 Year of Decision: 1846. New England Quarterly Awarded honorary Litt. D. by Kenyon College. Advance Agent. Mark Twain at Work.
1944 Strange Fruit The Woman in the Picture. The Literary Fallacy.
1946 Trip West in summer led to conservation work. The Portable Mark Twain
1947 Editor in chief of the History Book Club. Mountain Time. Across the Wide Missouri.
1948 Across the Wide Missouri.
1950 The World of Fiction.
1951 The Hour.
1952 Attacked by Senator Joseph McCarthy. The Course of Empire.
1953 Journals of Lewis and Clark Won National Book Award for best non-fiction of 1952.
1955 The Easy Chair.
1956 Women and Children First.
Other Biographical Sources
For additional material see the following:
Material in Box labeled "Biographical", including various genealogies, journals, a play concerning his life from 1920 to 1922, and the "Kent Potter" story.
Dissertation by Robert Edson Lee. (Includes a checklist of DeVoto's works).
Letters to DeVoto from Avis DeVoto and Marian M. Condliss.
Letters from DeVoto to Melville Smith, 1920-25
Letters from DeVoto to Robert Forsythe, 1927
Letters from DeVoto to Adrienne Burke, 3/27/44
Letters from DeVoto to Natl. Inst. of Arts and Letters, 12/22/47
Letters from DeVoto to Kate Sterne (safe) dated 10/6/27.
Pseudonyms: Cady Hewes; C.H.; John August; J.A.; Frank Gilbert; Richard Dye; Fairley Blake.
Scope and Content Note
The DeVoto Papers contain Bernard DeVoto's correspondence date from 1918 until his death in November 1955. The bulk of the correspondence was written between 1944 and 1951. The collection also includes manuscript, typescript and galley proof copies of nineteen major works, 166 articles, 25 short fiction and non-fiction items, and about 44 broadcasts, speeches and lectures.
Of primary interest is DeVoto's research material used in his literary output and in his life-long work in many fields, including politics, conservation and reclamation, free speech, the national park systems and Western Americana.
Correspondents include many of the leading figures in contemporary literature, politics, education and the arts. A partial list of the correspondents is included in the Optional Section of this register.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from the estate of Bernard DeVoto, 1956; supplemented by gifts from various sources.
Access
Collection is open for research. Please page materials at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
The family notes located in 1/22/466 are not to be photocopied although they may be read.
Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984; Alsop, Joseph, 1910-; Balch, E.; Barrett, Frank.; Beebe, Lucius.; Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977; Bowen, Catherine Drinker, 1897-; Brandt, Carl.; Briggs, L. B. R.; Brinton, Clarence Crane, 1898-1968.; Brooks, Paul, 1909-; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Bruner, Jerome Seymour.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Buley, R.; Bundy, McGeorge.; Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961.; Carhart, Arthur Hawthorne, 1892-; Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881.; Catton, Bruce, 1899-; Chamberlain, T. G.; Chandler, Raymond, 1888-1959.; Church, Frank; Collins, Carvel Emerson, 1912-; Cozzens, James Gould, 1903-; Crane, Hart, 1899-1932; Davis, Elmer.; De Voto, Bernard Augustine, 1897-1955; Dobie, J. Frank, (James Frank). 1888-1964.; Douglas, Paul Howard, 1892-; Edmonds, Walter Dumaux, 1903-; Edsall, John Tileston, 1902-; Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979.; Faulkner, William, 1897-1962.; Fischer, John, 1910 Apr. 27-; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Hicks, Granville, 1901-; Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911; Hillyer, Robert Silliman, 1895-; Holbrook, Stewart Hall, 1893-1964.; Hoover, J. Edgar, (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Howard, Joseph Kinsey, 1906-1951.; Hurlbut, B.; Hutchinson, W.; Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold Le Clair), 1874-1952.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Jones, Howard Mumford, 1892-; Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945.; King, G.; Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-; Kubie, Lawrence Schlesinger, 1896-; Lark, C. T.; Lattimore, Owen, 1900-; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951; Lindsay, Vachel, 1879-1931.; Little, Brown and Company.; Lodge, Henry Cabbot, 1850-1924.; Mansfield, Mike, 1903-; Marx, Groucho, 1891-1977.; Mattingly, Garrett, 1900-1962.; McCord, David Thompson Watson, 1897-; Mein, F.; Melville, Herman, 1819-1891; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Merk, Frederick, 1887-; Mirrielees, Edith R. (Edith Ronald), 1878-1962; Morgan, Dale Lowell, 1914-1971.; Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1887-1976.; Morrison, Theodore, 1901-; Moss, Frank E., 1911-; Murdock, Kenneth Ballard, 1895-1975.; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953.; Paine, Albert Bigelow, 1861-1937.; Perkins, Maxwell E. (Maxwell Evarts), 1884-1947; Porter, C.; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Pratt, Fletcher, 1897-1956.; Pulitzer, Joseph, 1847-1911.; Rhodes, Eugene Manlove, 1869-1934.; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-; Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967.; Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1917-; Spillane, Mickey, 1918.; Stassen, Harold Edward, 1907-; Stearns, Harold T. (Harold Thornton), 1900-; Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909-1993; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965; Stout, Rex, 1886-1975; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Wecter, Dixon, 1906-1950.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944; Wolfe, Thomas, 1900-1938.; Wylie, Philip, 1902-1971.; Articles.; Authors.; Conservation of natural resources.; Educators.; Galley proofs.; Historians.; Indians of North America.; Italy--Civilization--476-1268.; Lectures.; Lewis and Clark Expedition.; Liberty.; Manuscripts (literary); Maps.; Mormons--Utah--History.; National parks and reserves--United States.; Natural resources.; North Africa.; Photoprints; Speeches.; United States--History--1849-1877.; United States--History--1865-1921.; United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1953.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; West (U.S.)--History.
- Correspondence, 1918 - 1955; Series 1
  - Letters by Bernard De Voto (outgoing), May 1918 - November 1955.; Subseries 1.1
    Arrangement note
    arranged chronologically.
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1915-18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence to M. Smith; to C. Hagler. See also: "Kent Potter Story"., 1920-25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1922-27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1931 Jan.-Apr. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1931 May-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1933-34 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1937 Jan.-June (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1937 July-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1939 Jan.-May (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1939 June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1943 Jan.-May (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1943 June-Sept. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1943 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1944 Jan.-Feb. (Box 2, Folder 24.1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1944 March-Apr. (Box 2, Folder 24.2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1944 May (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1944 June-Sept. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1944 Oct.-Nov. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1944 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1945 Jan.-Feb. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1945 March-Apr. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1945 May (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1945 June-Sept. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1945 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1945 Nov.-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 Jan.; undated (Box 3, Folder 35.1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 35.2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 March (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 April (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 May (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 June-July (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 August-Sept. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1946 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 March 1-14 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 March 15-31 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 April 1-23 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 April 24-30 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 May 1-16 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 May 17-31 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 June 1-24 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 June 25-30 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 July (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 August (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Oct. 1-12 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Oct. 13-31 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Nov. 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Nov. 11-30 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Dec. 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1947 Dec. 16-31 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 Feb. (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 March 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 March 16-31 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 April (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 May 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 May 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 June 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 June 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 July 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 July 16-31 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 August (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 Nov. (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1948 Dec. (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 Jan. (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 Feb. (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 March (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 April (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 May (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 June (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 July-Aug. (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 Sept. (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 Oct. (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1949 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950 Jan. (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950 Feb. (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950 March-April (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950 May-June (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950 July-Aug. (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1950 Sept. -Dec. (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1952 Jan.-June (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1952 July-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1953 Jan.-March (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1953 April-May (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1953 June-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1954 Jan.-June (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1954 July-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1955 Jan.-Feb. (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1955 March-April (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1955 May-Nov. (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Outgoing correspondence, Undated (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Letters to BDV (incoming), Extensive cross-referencing for corporations, etc., Subseries 1.2
    arranged alphabetically by author and chronologically under each name.
    - Ables, G. - Adams, R.G., (8/46-4/47) (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Adams, R.G., (5-8/47) (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Adams, R.G., (Sept. 1947) (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Adams, R.G., (Oct.-Dec. 1947) (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Adams, R.G., (Jan.-April 1948) (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Agar, H. - Ajee, J. (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Albert, A. - Aley, B. (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Am. Antiquarian Society - American Magazine (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - American Mercury - Amory, C. (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Anders, H. - Anderson, S. (Box 7, Folder 118)
    - Anders, H. - Anderson, S. (Box 7, Folder 118)
    - Andrews, A. - Angostura (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - Appar, E. - Armstrong, C.J., (1931) (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Armstrong, C.J., (1932) (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Arnold, T. - Atwell, H. (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - Audubon - Aylewood, N. (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Bachrach, L. - Baker, R. (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Balch, E., (Aug. 1920 - June 1924) (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - Balch, E., (July 1924 - May 1925) (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Baldwin, L. - Baldwin, S. (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Balmer, E. - Barr, S. (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Barrett, A. - Bayley, C. (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Beach, H. - Becker, N.J. (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Beebe, L. (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Beer, S. - Benton, E. (Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Billinger, E. - Blair, W. (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Blake, F. - Blumenthal, J. (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Bobbs Merrill - Bovey, M. (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Bowen, C.D. (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Bowen, M. - Boynton, L. (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Bradley, S. - Branch, E. (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Brandt, C., (9-12/51) (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Brandt, C., (1-9/52) (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - Brandt, C., (10-12/52) (Box 8, Folder 141)
    - Brandt, C., (1-4/53) (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - Brandt, C., (5-12/53) (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - Brandt, C., (1-6/54) (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - Brandt, C., (7-12/54) (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Brandt, C., (1-7/55) (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Brandt, C., (8-11/55) (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Brandt, E. - Breed, Mrs. N., (1942) (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Breed, Mrs. N., (1/43-11/44) (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Breed, Mrs. N., (1/45-4/46) (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Brentanos - Briddell, C. (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - Briggs, L.B.R., (1/20-12/21) (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Briggs, L.B.R., (10-12/24) (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Briggs, L.B.R., (10/26 - 5/28) (Box 8, Folder 154)
    - Brigham, C. - Brinton, C. (Box 8, Folder 155)
    - Britannica - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 8, Folder 156)
    - Brower, D. - Brown Univ. Library (Box 8, Folder 157)
    - Brownell, G. (Box 8, Folder 158)
    - Browning, F. - Buker, M. (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Buley, R., (4-12/43) (Box 8, Folder 160)
    - Buley, R., (2-12/44) (Box 8, Folder 161)
    - Buley, R., (2/45-12/46) (Box 8, Folder 162)
    - Bulkley, R. - Burruss, T. (Box 8, Folder 163)
    - Burke, Harry R. (Box 8, Folder 164)
    - Burt, [?] - Burt, S. (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Burton, N. - Butterfield, A. (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - Butterfield, L. - Byrd, E. (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - "ECC" - Callaway, L. (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Cambridge Univ. - Capstone (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - Carhart, A., (1948 - (Box 9, Folder 170)
      Scope and Contents note
      see all material on conservation, 1940...)
    - Carhart, A., (1949-55) (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Carlson, A. - Calton, B. (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - Celler, E. - Chamberlain, J. (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Celler, E. - Chamberlain, J. (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (1943 - Jan. 1944 (Box 9, Folder 174)
      re Twain Estate; see also Breed Central Hanover Bank)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (1943 - Jan. 1944 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (2-5/44) (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (2-5/44) (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (7-12/44) (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (7-12/44) (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (1-5/45) (Box 9, Folder 177)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (1-5/45) (Box 9, Folder 177)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (6-12/45) (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (6-12/45) (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (1-4/46) (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (1-4/46) (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (4/46-5/48) (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Chamberlain, T.G., (4/46-5/48) (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Chamberlain, W. - Chaplean, E. (Box 9, Folder 181)
    - Chamberlain, W. - Chaplean, E. (Box 9, Folder 181)
    - Chapman, H. - Chapman, W. (Box 9, Folder 182)
    - Charles St. Meeting House Soc. - Cheynoneth, B. (Box 9, Folder 183)
    - Ciardi, J. - Civilian Defense (Box 9, Folder 184)
    - Clapp, E. - Clough, W. (Box 9, Folder 185)
    - Cobleutz, S. - Collier, N. (Box 9, Folder 186)
    - Colliers - Colorado, Univ. of (Box 9, Folder 187)
    - Colum, N. - Colwell, L. (Box 9, Folder 188)
    - Commager, H. - Congress, Library of (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - Conklin, G. - Cooke, A. (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - Cooke, M. - Copeland, C. (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - Corcorran Gallery - Coughlan, R. (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - Consius, N. - Cox, S. (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - Cragts, E. - Crown Publishers (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - Cullev, T. - Curtis Brown (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - Curtis, C. - Curtis, E. (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - Curtis, F. (Mrs. C.) - Curtis, Thomas (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - Fliss, D[?] - Davidson, J. (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - Davis, E., (1934-39) (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - Davis, E., (1940-42) (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - Davis, E., (1943-47) (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - Davis, E., (1948-50) (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - Davis, E., (1951-55) (Box 10, Folder 203)
    - Davis, H. - Dayton Public Library (Box 10, Folder 204)
    - Deal, B. - DeVries, W. (Box 10, Folder 205)
    - DeVoto, F., (1916, 1923-24) (Box 10, Folder 206)
      (BDV's father)
    - DeVoto, F., (1926-27) (Box 10, Folder 207)
      DeVoto, L.
    - Dewart, F. - Dilliard, L. (Box 10, Folder 208)
    - Dobie, F., (10/46-6/47) (Box 10, Folder 209)
      (See also: History Book Club)
    - Dobie, F., (7/47-7/48) (Box 10, Folder 210)
    - Dock, W. - Douglas, E. (Box 11, Folder 211)
    - Douglas, P. - Drury, N. (Box 11, Folder 212)
    - Dugan, M. - Dystel, O. (Box 11, Folder 213)
    - Eagin, F. - Edwards, M. (Box 11, Folder 214)
    - Eggert, C. - Ely, N. (Box 11, Folder 215)
    - Embree, E. - Eshelman, L. (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Esquire - Ewing, J. (Box 11, Folder 217)
    - Fadiman, C. - Farrara, F. (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - Farrel, J. - Ferguson, D. (Box 11, Folder 219)
    - Ferril, T. (Box 11, Folder 220)
    - Ferris, P. - Ferry, R. (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - Fielack, S. - Fitzgerald, W. (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - Flack, F. - Flynn, J. T. (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - Foote, F. - Ford, W. (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - Forest Preserve (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - Forest Service, U.S. Dept. of Agric., Bureau of, (1945-9) (Box 11, Folder 226)
    - Forest Service, (1950-55) (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - Forester, M. - Fox, E. (Box 11, Folder 228)
    - Franchot, S. - Frost, D. (Box 11, Folder 229)
    - Frost, R. (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - Frothingham, C. - Furth, A. (Box 11, Folder 231)
    - "J.M.G." - Gabrilowitsch, C. (Box 12, Folder 232)
    - Gaillard, W. - Garwin, M. (Box 12, Folder 233)
    - Geddes, D. - Gjullin, H. (Box 12, Folder 234)
    - Glasgow, E. - Gould, E. (Box 12, Folder 235)
    - Graeber, I. - Grayson, C. (Box 12, Folder 236)
    - Green, A. - Gregory, E. (Box 12, Folder 237)
    - Griffith, D. - Guthrie, B. (Box 12, Folder 238)
    - "A.D.H." - Haller, R. (Box 12, Folder 239)
    - Halliday, R. (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Hapern, S. - Harper, J. (Box 12, Folder 241)
    - Harper and Brothers, (9/28-10/40) (Box 12, Folder 242)
    - Harper and Brothers, (4/41-2/44) (Box 12, Folder 243)
    - Harper and Brothers, (3/44-11/47) (Box 12, Folder 244)
    - Harper and Brothers, (3/48-9/55) (Box 12, Folder 245)
    - Harper's Magazine, (1931-42) (Box 12, Folder 246)
    - Harper's Magazine, (1944-47) (Box 12, Folder 247)
    - Harper's Magazine, (1948) (Box 12, Folder 248)
    - Harper's Magazine, (1949-50) (Box 12, Folder 249)
    - Harper's Magazine, (1951-55) (Box 12, Folder 250)
    - Harris, B. - Hartwell, K. (Box 12, Folder 251)
    - Harvard University (Box 12, Folder 252)
    - Harvey, M. - Hazard, Mrs. F. (Box 13, Folder 253)
    - Healy, A. - Henry, R. (Box 13, Folder 254)